Guide to the Athletics and Recreation Department records, 1890-2009 RG0054
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- GW Spirit Program, circa 1980-2008; RG0054 Series 44; 4 artifact(s) 1 over-size textile box and 3 over-sized custom boxes.
  - George mascot heads (belong to George costumes 2 and 3), RG0054 Series 44; 2 artifact(s) 1 oversize box (Box 3, Object 2, Object 1)
- Athletics Communications Office files and publications, 1933-2015; RG0054 Series 45
  This series contains various photos, newspaper clippings, press releases, and statistics as collected by the GW Athletics Department. Boxes are arranged by sport and files are arranged by playing season and/or year.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  - Men's Baseball Newspaper Clippings, 1933-1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Men's Baseball Note from Doug Gould, 1969-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Men's Baseball Photos, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Men's Baseball Statistics and Brochures, 1969-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Men's Baseball Newspaper Clippings, 1978-1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Men's Baseball Undated Photos (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Men's Baseball Photos, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Men's Baseball Alumni Game Photo, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Men's Baseball Photos, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Men's Baseball Unmarked Photos from Coach Murphy's Era (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Men's Baseball Photos, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Men's Baseball Photos, 1986-1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Men's Baseball Team Photos, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Men's Baseball Undated Photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Men's Baseball Photos and Brochures, 1978-1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Men's Baseball Statistics and Brochures, 1993-2004 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Men's Baseball Photos, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Men's Baseball, 1989-1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Men's Baseball NCAA Game vs Navy Photos, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Women's Volleyball Misc. Team Photos, 1975-1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Women's Volleyball Photos, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Women's Volleyball Head Coach Cindy Laughlin, 1980-1990 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Women's Volleyball Head Coach Susan Homan, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Women's Rowing Photos, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Women's Rowing Photos, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Men's and Women's Crew Classic Pamphlets, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Women's Rowing Photos, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Women's Rowing A10 Championship, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Women's Rowing Photos, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Undated Women's Rowing Photos (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Men's Rowing Photos, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Men's Rowing Photos, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Men's and Women's Rowing, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Men's Rowing Photos, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Undated Men's Rowing Photos (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Men's Wrestling Photos and Brochures, 1968-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Men's and Women's Cross Country Photos and Brochures, 1993-2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Women's Tennis Photos, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Women's Tennis Photos, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Women's Tennis Photos, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Women's Tennis Photos, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Women's Tennis Photos, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Women's Tennis Photos, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Men's and Women's Tennis Photos, 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Women's Badminton, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Men's and Women's Swimming and Diving, 2000-2009 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Men's Football Photos, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Women's Gymnastics Photos, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Women's Gymnastics Photos, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Men's and Women's Soccer, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Men's Water Polo, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Men's Golf Photos and Pamhplet, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Men's Badminton Undated Photo of Don Paup (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Men's Basketball Press Releases and Statistics, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Men's Basketball Game Program, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Men's Basketball Game Program, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Men's Basketball Game Program, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Men's Basketball Game Program, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Men's Basketball Statistics and Projected Statistics, 1967-05 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Men's Basketball Press Release Regarding Bob Tallent, GWU Coach, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Men's Basketball Post-Season Statistics and Info, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Men's Basketball Statistics and Brochures, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Men's Basketball Statistics, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Men's Basketball Statistics, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Women's Basketball Brochures A10 Championship Games, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Men's Basketball Miscellaneous Photos, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - GWU Archives - Brief History (Regarding Athletics and the College), 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Men's Basketball NCAA Champs Game Info and Stats, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Men's and Women's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Men's Basketball NCAA Championships Game Pamphlet, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Men's Basketball Media Guide NCAA Champs Game 2002 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Men's Basketball various pamphlets, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Men's Basketball Pamphlet (from the Hatchet), 2005-2006 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Men's Basketball Sports Illustrated for NCAA Champs Games, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Men's Basketball NCAA Boxscores, 1993-2007 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Men's Basketball Post-Season Boxscores, 1954-2007 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Men's Basketball NIT Season Pamphlet, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Men's Basketball various pamphlets and magazines, 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Men's Basketball Statistics Packets, 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Men's Basketball Statistics and Brochures, 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Men's Basketball Statistics Packets, 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Men's Basketball Statistics Packets, 2015-2016 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Misc. Matter GWU Athletics Word Division Manuals, 1952-1968 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Men's Basketball Misc. Undated Newspaper Clipping (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Men's Basketball Misc. Undated Photos (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - GWU Athletics Unmarked B&W Photo (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Women's Basketball Photos, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Women's Basketball Team Photos, 1992-1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Women's Basketball Head Coach Joe McKeown Photos, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Women's Basketball Head Coach Tori Harrison Photos, 1999-2004 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Women's Basketball Photos US Olympics Festival, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Men's Basketball Photos, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Men's Basketball Team Photo, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Men's Basketball Head Coach John Kuester, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Men's Basketball Head Coach John Kuester Photos, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Men's Basketball Misc. Older Photos, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Men's Basketball Assistant Coach Rodney Johnson, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Men's Basketball Head Coach Tom Penders, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Men's Basketball Auerbach Golf Tourney Photos, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Men's Basketball Photos NCAA, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Men's Basketball, The "Basket Ball" Photos, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Men's Basketball etc. undated photos (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Men's Basketball Defensive Specialist 1937-1940 Arnold "Red" Auerbach, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Men's Basketball Defensive Specialist 1937-1940 Arnold "Red" Auerbach, photos and articles, 1980-2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Men's Basketball March Madness Articles and News Clippings, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Men's Basketball Articles and Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Men's Basketball Press Clippings NCAA, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Men's Basketball Press Clippings NCAA, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings Spring, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Men's Basketball News Clippings, 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Men's Basketball and Newspaper Clippings, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Men's Basketball Newspaper Clippings, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Misc. Athletics Articles and Brochures, 1984-1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Men's All-Star Basketball Game Smith Center, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Photos of Smith Center, Reagan Institute, etc., 1961-1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - GWU Athletics Jason Wilson, Operations Coordinator photo (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Men's Basketball Highlight Tape Notes and Order Forms c/o Brad Bower, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Athletics Hall of Fame Jay Randolph (Class of 1956), Golf Inductee, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Various Invoices, H. Bloomberg and T. Carson, 2015 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Expense Reimbursements c/o Jesse Hooker, Dir. of Athletics Communications, 2011-2015 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - General Clippings, Notes, Photos, 1975-2010 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - General Clippings, Notes, Photos, 1975-2010 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Men's Basketball Highlights, Games, and Shows, 2004-2005 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Men's Basketball Highlights, Games, and Shows, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Men's and Women's Basketball Slides, 1989-2001 (Box 9)
    This box contains various photo slides of the men's and women's basetball teams.
    Files are arranged in folders by team and year.
  - Misc. Athletics Slides, 1980-2001 (Box 11)
    This box contains various slides from men's and women's sports, including basketball, baseball, soccer, golf, and crew.
    Files are arranged by year. Many photo slides are in storage boxes (some labelled, some not).
  - Men's and Women's Basketball Slides, 1997-2001 (Box 12)
    This box contains various photo slides from the men's and women's basektball teams.
    Slides are organized into storage boxes (some labelled, some not).
  - Men's Basketball Slides, 1993-2001 (Box 13)
    This box contains various photo slides of the men's basketball team.
    Most slides are labelled and kept in their original manilla envelopes.
  - Misc. Athletics Slides, 1976-2003 (Box 14)
    This box contains various men's and women's photo slides (mostly basketball and volleyball).
    Files are organized in either folders or their original manilla envelopes, and are arranged by sport and year.
  - Men's and Women's Soccer Photos, 1971-2001 (Box 15)
    This box contains various photos from the men's and women's soccer teams.
    Photos are arranged by team and year.
  - Various Men's and Women's Athletics Photos, 1976-2001 (Box 16)
    This box contains various photos of both men's and women's athletics teams, including cross-country, soccer, swimming, water polo, badminton, special events, and cheerleading. It also contains one folder of photos of George, the GW mascot.
    Photos are arranged within folders by sport and year.
  - Various Special Events Files, 1960-2008 (Box 18)
    This box contains files on admittees to GW's athletic Hall of Fame, as well as some testimonials and information regarding faculty and/or coach retirement.
    Folders are arranged by person and, in the case of hall of famers, labelled by year of graduation and year of admittance.
  - Various Athlete, Coach, and Hall of Fame Files, 1959-2010 (Box 19)
    This box contains various files of GW athletes and coaches, and some admittees to the Hall of Fame.
    Folders are arranged by person, and include graduation year (if a student), years worked at GW (if a faculty member or coach), and/or year admitted (if admitted to Hall of Fame).
  - Football Letterman, Men's Soccer Photos, and Gene Kerin Files, 1955-1998 (Box 20)
    This box contains documentation of GW football letterwinners, two binders of photo and slides of the men's soccer team (from 1989-1998), and one folder containing information on Gene Kerin, a wrestling coach.
    Lettermen folders are arranged by year.
  - Various Photos and Clippings from Men's and Women's Athletics, 1983-2009 (Box 21)
    This box contains various photos and news clippings from men's and women's sports.
  - Men's and Women's Basketball Game Highlights and News Clippings, 1998-2015 (Box 22)
    This box contains documents related to men's and women's basketball, including news clippings and game highlights. Game highlights exist on both CDs and VHS tapes, and some are unmarked.
  - Basketball Players and Coaches, 1997-2011 (Box 23)
    This box contains profiles of basketball players and coaches (mostly men's) and some miscellaneous athletics clippings and magazines.
  - Men's and Women's Misc. Athletics Press Clippings, 1978-2000 (Box 24)
    This box contains miscellaneous press clippings highlighting various men's and women's teams, including basketball, swimming, and crew.
  - Various Hall of Fame Files and Player Posters, 1959-2010 (Box 17)
    This box contains files on admittees (last names A-E) to GW's athletic Hall of Fame, as well as one folder of player posters.
  - Various Men's and Women's Sport Photographs, 2000-2011 (Box 25)
    Photos are on CDs in six holders, and photos of the women's basketball team from 2000-2001 are on slides in a binder. The CDs are in original order and are arranged roughly by dates of creation. The files on the CDs are named for the events they include photos of.
    Box contains about fifty CDs spread among six holders that contain photographs of various GW sports teams during games and ceremonial events from the years 2000-2011. Box also contains one binder of about 300 slides. The sports covered include baseball, softball, basketball, swimming, diving, crew, and volleyball.
  - Men's and Women's Sports Photographs and News Articles, 1950-2010 (Box 26)
    Folders are in original order. Contents are groups by sport and year, but folders do not appear to be arranged in any specific order.
    Folders contain negatives, photographs, newspaper articles, and printed articles depicting or referencing GW sports teams from the 1950s-2000s.
  - Sports Print Media and Advertising, 1994-2000 (Box 27)
    Box contains issues of The Hatchet, sports program brochures, and various other reserach materials for relating to Hatchet articles.
    Materials came to archives loose in a box, so no original order was present. Materials are not in a specific order in current container.
  - Basketball News Articles and Promotional Material, 1990-2000 (Box 28)
    Materials are in original order with orginal folder titles maintained. Folders in current container are not in a particular order.
    Box contains newspaper articles and other print media relating to GW basketball team. It also has other promotional matierals for the team, and a few player related items like varsity letters.